A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, AIA-IBEC, Series B FA339
Rockefeller Archive Center
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - Federal Corporation Income Taxes, 1948-1966 (Box 38, Folder 350)
  Correspondence re: annual filing of federal tax return; copies of each return 1949 to final return (corp. liquidated December 30, 1965).
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - New York State Franchise Taxes, 1949-1965 (Box 38, Folder 351)
  Correspondence re: New York State Franchise Tax Return, checks; copies of return for each year 1949 to date of dissolution (cessation report); tax receipts.
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - IBEC Securities Co., Inc., 1948-1949 (Box 38, Folder 352)
  By-laws, certificate of incorporation of IBEC Securities Corp., miscellaneous correspondence re: IBEC Securities and IBEC Investing; memorandum on "IBEC Securities Corporation," 1949.
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - IBEC Securities Co., Inc. - Incorporation Papers, 1948-1949 (Box 38, Folder 353)
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - [Charter, By Laws, Minutes, Endorsed Certificate of Incorporation], 1949 (Box 39, Folder 354)
  "IBEC Investing Corporation"; charter, by-laws, minutes (up to dissolution).
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - Book of Accounts, 1949-1965 (Box 39, Folder 355)
- IBEC - Investing Corporation - Corporate Seal (Box 39, Folder 356)
  Corporate Seal of IBEC Investing Corporation.
- Estudio de Operaciones en Puerto de La Guaira, Venezuela, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 357)
- Informe Sobre La Industria del Calzado en Venezuela, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 358)
- Arterial Plan of Caracas, Venezuela, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 359)
- Survey of Operations at Port of La Guaira, Venezuela, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 360)
- Annual Report, Appendix, 1949-1951 (Box 40, Folder 361)
- El Mercado Libre, 1949-1951 (Box 40, Folder 362)
- Annual Report CIDEA (Inter-American Council on Nutrition Education), 1949-1951 (Box 40, Folder 363)
- Photographs, mounted, AIA, 1950-1951 (Box 40, Folder 364)
- "Industrial Potentials of Ireland" IBEC Technical Services Corporation, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 365)
- Audiovisual materials, 1
  Scope and Contents
  The RAC has a collection of films in English and Spanish made for the use of IBEC, including films on tropical diets, agricultural practices and improvements, housing in Puerto Rico, and food production.
  Biographical / Historical
  The American International Association for Economic and Social Development was established by Nelson Rockefeller in 1946 as an outgrowth of his work as Coordinator for Inter-American Affairs. With a similar mission, the International Basic Economy Corporation was established in 1947 to enhance the economic and social growth of developing countries, particularly in Latin America.
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
  If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
  - La Batilla Contra La Huja Blanca (Reel AV 1263)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    produced by AIA/El Observador Creole/Bolivar Films, Curacas, Venezuela
    File Plan
    IV 3B2 Fb 2
  - Good Diets in the Tropics (Reel AV 870)
    Produced by AIA/Knickerbocker Productions for Consejo Informativo de Educacion Alimenticia (Advisory Board on Food and Education); producer Schuyler Bradt, director Victor Solow
    IV 3B2 Fd 7
  - Crucito: Una Realizacion de Extension Agricola (Reel AV 1262)
    Produced by IBEC/Ministry of Culture/ABN Film Production, Caracas, Venezuela
    IV 3B2 Fb 1
  - El Cultivo del Cafe in Venezuela (The Cultivation of Coffee in Venezuela), 1958 (Reel AV 1260)
    Produced by MAC Film, with CBR Coordination/ABN Film
    IV 3B2 Fd 4
  - The IBEC System of Low-Cost Housing Construction, 1949; Sound, Black and white, 15 minutes (Reel AV 1093)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
    Overview of techniques and machinery used to construct inexpensive concrete homes, based on plan by Nelson A. Rockefeller and architect Wallace K. Harrison. Film documents the development of low-cost housing in Norfolk, Virginia. Produced by RKO/Pathe.
  - La Produccion de Leche (Milk Production) (Reel AV 1526)
    Produced by Aquila Films/MAC/CBR
    IV 382 Fd 1
  - Semeando Para u Futuro (Seeding the Future) (Reel AV 1264)
    Dramatic portrayal of ACAR/IBE projects to improve agricultural, economic, and social conditions in Brazil, told through the story of a poor tobacco farmer and his family. The organizations introduce "modern methods" for irrigation and planting, harvest and milling, washing, cooking, and others. Produced by AIA/Cine Films, with Herbert Riche.
    IV 3B2 Fd 5
  - Lomas Verdes, 1956 August 4 (Reel AV 1092)
    WAPA TV news piece on Lomas Verdes August 4, 1956.
    IV 3B21 Fa 3
  - This is America: Rockefeller Center (Reel AV 1088, Reel AV 1259)
    An RKO newsreel relating to IBEC projects
    IV 3B2 Fd 2 (AV 1088), and IV 3B2 Fd 2 (AV 1088)
  - Vineta Verficando Posibilidados en Oriente (Survey for the Future in Eastern Venezuela) (Reel AV 1526)
    A summary of research being conducted in hopes of improving agricultural development, as well as aiding social and economic causes. Produced by El Observador Creole/Bolivar Films
    IV 3B2 Fb 4
  - Visita Ministro Iraq y Sr. Rockefeller, 1957 September 21 (Reel AV 1090)
    Winthrop Rockefeller visits IBEC housing projects with Iraqi ministers in Puerto Rico
    IV 3B21 Fa 1
  - Weed and Brush Control (Reel AV 1522)
    Tradewind Air Spray, Amarillo, Texas
    IV 3B21 Ff 1
  - Youth Club Achievement Day (Reel AV 1817)
    Display of traditional cooking, dancing, farming, and fashion styles by youth clubs in Aragua, Venezuela. Presented to administrators, foreign visitors, and military personnel.
    IV 3B2 Fc 1
  - Telemando TV-WKAQ, 1956; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes. Only available on 16mm film. (Reel AV 1091)
    IV 3B21 Fa 2
    Puerto Rican TV news piece on Lomas Verdes and the IBEC Housing Corp of Puerto Rico August 5, 1956.